Consuming food can be a pleasurable thing - we enjoy feasting on the mix of tastes and textures and it stops us feeling hungry too.
进食可以是一件令人愉悦的事情-我们喜欢尽情享受各种味道和口感的混合，而且它还能让我们不再感到饥饿。
Of course, food also gives us energy and the vitamins and minerals that our body needs.
当然，食物也为我们提供能量以及我们身体所需的维他命和矿物质。
It‘s no wonder we spend so much time preparing and eating food.
难怪我们会花这么多时间准备和进食。
But what many of us don’t consider is how our emotions are affected by what we put into our bellies.
但我们很多人没有考虑到的是，我们吃进肚子里的东西是如何影响我们的情绪的。
For me, it‘s the unhealthy foods that put a smile on my face - chocolate, cakes and ice cream - well, I do have a sweet tooth!
对我来说，是那些不健康的食物让我开心-巧克力、蛋糕和冰淇淋-嗯，我确实喜欢吃甜食！
It might seem obvious that food that’s bad for our waistline, usually makes us happy, at least in the short term.
很明显，对我们腰围有害的食物通常会让我们开心，至少在短期内是这样。
Most of us get this feeling when we use food as a quick pick-me-up.
当我们把食物当作快速提神的东西时，我们大多数人都会有这种感觉。
But dieticians tell us that eating bad food long term, not only makes us put on weight but can lead to other health conditions such as diabetes, and it can also affect our mental state and bring on depression.
但是营养学家告诉我们，长期食用不健康的食物，不仅会让我们体重增加，还可能导致其他健康问题，比如糖尿病，而且它还会影响我们的精神状态，引发抑郁症。
The link between our mind and food has been looked at by scientists.
科学家们已经研究了我们的心理和食物之间的联系。
They‘ve recently found that it’s the bacteria in our gut that affects our mood.
他们最近发现，是我们肠道中的细菌影响着我们的情绪。
It‘s thought we have 39 trillion of these simple, small organisms in our body.
据认为，我们体内有39万亿个这样简单的小生物。
Researchers at McMaster University in Canada and University College Cork in Ireland, have found that certain ’good‘ bacteria help reduce anxiety in mice.
加拿大麦克马斯特大学和爱尔兰科克大学学院的研究人员发现，某些“有益”细菌有助于减轻老鼠的焦虑感。
And researchers at Kyushu University also found that germs help reduce stress and anxiety in mice.
九州大学的研究人员也发现，微生物有助于减轻老鼠的压力和焦虑。
Experts believe that, for us humans, this means food with ’good‘ bacteria can improve the way we feel.
专家们认为，对我们人类来说，这意味着含有“有益”细菌的食物可以改善我们的感受。
Many food products are claiming to be high in this ’good‘ bacteria and some of the best types are homemade fermented food like miso soup, yoghurt and sauerkraut.
许多食品都声称含有大量这种“有益”细菌，其中一些最好的种类是自制发酵食品，比如味增汤、酸奶和酸菜。
This really makes me think twice about what I eat — maybe I should change my diet to perk me up!
这真的让我重新审视自己的饮食——也许我应该改变我的饮食来让自己振作起来！
Doctor Michael Mosley would agree.
迈克尔·莫斯利医生会同意这一点。
He’s been looking into this for the BBC and says the best food to cheer us up is in a “Mediterranean diet.
他一直在为英国广播公司研究这个问题，他说让我们振作起来的最佳食物来自“地中海饮食”。
Olive oil; oily fish, full of omega 3, which is really good for the brain; whole grains; lots of fruits and vegetables.
橄榄油；富含欧米伽3脂肪酸的油性鱼类，这对大脑非常有益；全谷物；大量的水果和蔬菜。
Sugar: terrible for you!”
而糖：对你的身体来说是很糟糕的！
So maybe it‘s time to lay off the fatty and sugary things.
所以，也许是时候少吃那些高脂肪和高糖的食物了。
Eating healthily may seem simple, even if the science behind it is complex.
健康饮食可能看起来很简单，即使其背后的科学原理很复杂。
It’s not rocket science but this is further evidence for the saying ‘we are what we eat‘ — the person we are is determined by the food we eat.
这不是什么高深的学问，但这进一步证明了“人如其食”这句谚语——我们是什么样的人取决于我们吃的食物。
There are other factors that can change our mood but it seems we have some ability to improve how we feel by controlling what we put on our plate.
还有其他因素可以改变我们的情绪，但似乎我们有一定的能力通过控制我们的饮食来改善我们的感受。
Does your diet affect your mood?
你的饮食会影响你的情绪吗？